(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
アイドル革命進行中！今日の主役は夢の途中
Idol Revolution in Progress! Today's Protagonist is in the Middle of a Dream
世界一可愛い私
The cutest me in the world
宇宙一可愛い
The cutest in the universe
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more
ご褒美は目を閉じて
My reward is, close your eyes...
チュッ
Chu!
見つけてくれてサンキュー
Thank you for finding me
愛してくれてサンキュー
Thank you for loving me
生きがいにしちゃってもいいのよ
It's okay if I become your reason for living
一人じゃ無理だ逆境
Adverse circumstances are too much for one person
みんながいれば最強
With everyone, I'm the strongest
見つめ合って両思い、好きになっちゃえ
Looking at each other, our love is mutual, go on and fall in love!
涙じゃ何も解決しないの分かってるから
Because I know that tears don't solve anything
だから
So...
言葉で　行動で見せるよ
I'll show you with my words and actions
覚悟はいい？
Are you ready?
世界一可愛い
I'm the cutest in the world
宇宙一可愛い
The cutest in the universe
もっともっと声出して
Let me hear your voices more and more
よそ見はダメ　オッケー？
Don't look away, okay?
瞬きも可愛い
Even my blinks are cute
存在が可愛い
My very existence is cute
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear you more and more
ご褒美は...
The reward is...
目ぇ閉じて　チュッ
Close your eyes... Chu!
歌ってくれてサンキュー
Thank you for singing along
笑顔くれてサンキュー
Thank you for the smiles
生きててよかったって思った
It made me feel so glad to be alive
ちょっとのミスは愛嬌
A little mistake is just charm
だけどやる気は最強
But my motivation is the strongest
競い合って高め合って　全部で行こう
Let's compete and improve together, let's go with everything we've got
苦手ずっと逃げてちゃ　愛は届かないから
If I keep running away from my weaknesses, love won't reach
だから何度も何度も挑もう
So I'll challenge myself over and over again
楽しんじゃお！
Let's have some fun!
あざとくて可愛い
I'm calculatedly cute
最高に可愛い
The absolute cutest
私だけを笑って
Smile only for me
よそ見はダメ　オッケー？
Don't look away, okay?
瞬きも可愛い
Even my blinks are cute
存在が可愛い
My very existence is cute
ずっとずっと聞かせて
Let me hear you forever and ever
輝くから
Because I'll shine
約束ね
It's a promise
上手に歌えてるかな
I wonder if I'm singing well
上手に踊れてるかな
I wonder if I'm dancing well
間違うの怖くなるけど
I get scared of making mistakes, but...
できる　できる　できる　できる　そうだ
I can do it, I can do it, I can do it, I can do it... That's right
信じてくれる人がいる
There's someone who believes in me
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
Through this song, I can stay connected with you
忘れられないストーリー描いていこう
Let's paint an unforgettable story
行くよー！
Here we go!
世界一可愛い
I'm the cutest in the world
宇宙一可愛い
The cutest in the universe
もっともっと声出して
Let me hear your voices more and more
よそ見はダメ　オッケー？
Don't look away, okay?
瞬きも可愛い
Even my blinks are cute
存在が可愛い
My very existence is cute
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear you more and more
ご褒美は...
The reward is...
目ぇ閉じて　チュッ
Close your eyes... Chu!
今日も鏡をチェック　最高の笑顔届ける
Checking the mirror again today, delivering the best smile
才能に甘えないの
I won't just rely on talent
努力が大事や
Effort is what matters
お勉強して
I'll study properly
お片付けする
And clean up properly
正体は私はそうアイドルだもん
In truth, I'm an idol after all
好きなタイプは私　大好きでマジ一途な人
My type is someone who loves me and is seriously devoted
ぴったりの君だけど
You're a perfect match
今はじゃない目ぇ閉じて
But not right now, close your eyes
理想はもっと大人だけど　君だけのものに
My ideals are even more mature, but to be only yours...
なれないの　あぁごめん
...I can't, ah, sorry
いつまでも好きでいて　約束よ
Keep loving me forever, it's a promise
わがままな御願いね　みんなのものでいたい
It's a selfish request, I want to belong to everyone
それでも私のこと好きですか？
Even so, do you still love me?
ピンク色のフリフリ　スポットライト浴びて
Pink frills, bathed in the spotlight
いつかきっとね　君だけの私に
One day, surely, I'll be only yours
今はまだ歌いたい
For now, I still want to sing
現役アイドル中
Currently an active idol
ずっとワクワクなのよ おかず作らなくちゃ
I'm always so excited! I've got to make some side dishes
お気に入りパックしちゃうんだ
and pack my favorites!
キラキラメイクは今日もバッチリ
Sparkly makeup is perfect again today.
やっと君と出会えた
I finally got to meet you.
ちょっと話せるだけなのになんか...
Just being able to talk for a bit makes me feel...
また今日も早起きして
I woke up early again today
二人の時間を楽しみにしてるから
because I'm looking forward to our time together.
握手会 コンサート 会いに来て
Come see me at handshake events and concerts!
君のハッピーなその顔 ずっと覚えているわ
I'll always remember that happy face of yours.
今週も来週も会いたいな
I want to see you this week and next week too.
おしゃれなお洋服も準備して待ってるね
I'll be waiting with my stylish clothes ready.
雨の日も風の日も頑張る君の姿は
I'll always love the way you work hard
いつまでも好きでいる
through rain and wind.
オフィシャル両思い
Official mutual love.
私と出会えた人にありがとう
Thank you to everyone I've met.
こんなにキュートな私でいちゃうもん
Because I'm going to stay this cute!
くるくるレースもひらり回ってる
Round and round, the lace is fluttering too.
いくつになってもこのままここで輝く
No matter how old I get, I'll keep shining right here.
ねぇねぇ教えて なぁに？
Hey, hey, tell me. What is it?
今日も可愛い？
Am I cute today too?
可愛いよー！
You're cute!
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Love me forever, it's a promise.
私だって君のこと ずっとずっと大好き
I love you so, so much too, forever and ever.
一生私のこと好きですか？
Will you love me for the rest of your life?
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライト浴びて
Basking in the spotlight in my pink frills.
いつかきっとね 君だけの私に
Someday, for sure, I'll be yours alone.
今はまだ歌いたい
For now, I still want to sing.
現役アイドル中
Currently an active idol!
わーーー！みんなー！せーの！
Waaaaa! Everyone! One, two...!
こんばんわっしょい！
Konban-wasshoi!
どうもホロライブの清楚担当
Hello! I'm Hololive's 'purity' representative
みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりでーす！
and everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
ということで、今年もやってきました！
And so, it's here again this year!
遅ればせながらの、生誕、誕生祭でございますよ！
My slightly belated birthday celebration festival!
まつりちゃんの誕生日は7月の22日なんでございますが
My birthday is July 22nd...
まあ、あの周年の6月ということで
well, since my anniversary is in June...
毎年11月にやらさせていただいております
we hold this in November every year.
なので今日も実質誕生日でございますね
So today is practically my birthday too.
はい、おめでとう、ありがとうございます。
Yes, happy birthday to me, thank you!
そして本日のハッシュタグはこちら！ドドドドド
And today's hashtag is this! *drumroll*
#夏色まつり誕生祭2025 でございます！
It's #NatsuiroMatsuriBirthday2025!
いっぱいツイートしてトレンドに入れてあげてください、お願いします！
Please tweet a lot and get it trending, I'm counting on you!
あのスクショとかもね、撮っていただいたりとか
Take some screenshots and stuff...
あとツイートしてくれたら、まつりちゃんが後でエゴサさせていただきますので
and if you tweet them, I'll be ego-searching later!
ぜひよろしくお願いしますね、見ちゃうよ見ちゃうよ
So please do, I'll be watching, I'll be watching!
はい。そしてね、まあ、皆さんもお気づきかなと思います。
Yes. And, well, I think you've all noticed.
本日のタイトル「アイドル革命進行中！～今日の主役は夢の途中～」というタイトルにもあるようにでございますね
As suggested by today's title, 'Idol Revolution in Progress! ~Today's Protagonist is in the Middle of a Dream~'...
本日はアイドルさんの曲をたくさん詰め込んだ
today is a live show packed with many idol songs
超とってもとっても可愛くて
that's super-duper cute,
ポップで、キュートで、ワクワクするようなライブになっていますので
pop, and exciting!
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy it until the end!
よろしくお願いします！
I'm counting on you!
コメントでもサイリウムを振ったりとか
Please leave lots of comments, wave your lightsticks,
可愛いよーって言っちゃったりとか、たくさんしてくださいね！
and tell me I'm cute!
ということで、この後は皆さんお待ちかねのゲストパート！
And so, next is the guest part you've all been waiting for!
やったー！
Yay!
はい、ちょっとね...
Yes, so...
あの、まつりちゃん、本家ダンスとかが、すごく大好きなので...
Um, Matsuri-chan really loves the original dances and such...
あの、レッスンで、「おねがい、やらせてください」って言って...
So, during lessons, I asked, "Please, let us do this."
フォーメーションとかも含め、みんなには頑張ってもらっていますので...
Including the formations and everything, everyone has worked really hard on it...
あの、君の推しがもしいたら、褒めてあげてください。
So, if your oshi is among them, please give them lots of praise.
ということで、ゲストパート準備してきちゃいますね。
And with that, I'm going to get ready for the guest part.
じゃあ、みんな「わくわく」ってコメントして待ってて。
So, everyone, please comment "Waku Waku" while you wait.
じゃあ、行ってきまーい！
Well then, here I go!
わくわく、わくわく、わくわく、わくわく、わくわく。
Waku waku, waku waku, waku waku, waku waku, waku waku.
サクラあっぱれーしょん
作詞・作曲：玉屋2060% (Wienners)
Sakura Abare-shon
Lyrics & Music: Tamaya2060% (Wienners)
Hey Yo! P.M.P.M. from 秋葉原 to Every Area
Hey Yo! P.M.P.M. from Akihabara to Every Area
さあさ寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい　もう一切合切やっちゃいな
Come one, come all, check it out! Let's do it all!
ありったけの可愛いと楽しいこと詰め込んで
Packing in all the cuteness and fun we can find
千客万来　船に乗って　いざ出航だー！
A full house! Get on the boat, it's time to set sail!
Hey Yo! P.M.P.M. from Japanese Heart Area
みんな元気ですか？ 声聞かせて はい 電波！ (電波！)
Is everyone doing well? Let me hear your voices! Yes, Dempa! (Dempa!)
ありがとう！ 準備はバッチリのようだな (OK!)
Thank you! It looks like you're all ready! (OK!)
今から愉快な船に乗って　いざ出航だー！
Now let's board the jolly ship and set sail!
さあみんなダンス！ダンス！ダンス！　拳入って　ひらりひらり
Now everyone dance! Dance! Dance! Put some spirit into it, fluttering around
かっこつけて　バッバッバッ　ハミ出てう～
Looking cool, bam-bam-bam, bursting out, ooh~
めちゃくちゃな状況　めでたり　それが僕らにとってのファンタジー
Celebrating a chaotic situation, that's what's fantasy to us
しゅっ！と　しゅっ！と　感じるんだ　酔ってるんだ　ソレ！ソレ！ソレ！ソレ！
Flash! Flash! Feel it, getting drunk on it! Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
しっ！しっ！しっ！　胸張って　あせったリ　ズレてても　コジコジ逆方向
Shih! Shih! Shih! Chest out, getting flustered, even if we're off, we're going the other way
青春はそれでいいのだ　勘違いも味方にしちゃうのだ
Youth is fine like that, we'll even make misunderstandings our allies
シンバンショー！　お祭り日本！　踊れ日本！　アソレ！ソレ！ソレ！　（よいしょー！）
Shin-ban-sho! Festival Japan! Dance, Japan! A-sore! Sore! Sore! (Yoisho!)
疾風迅雷！　どこまでも　ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
With lightning speed! To the ends of the earth, look, break through with full power
あっちもこっちもそっちも　お祭りだワッショイ　あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
大和撫子　ええなもし　不思議な言霊
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a festival, Wasshoi! A magnificent, magnificent adventure
Yamato Nadeshiko, how lovely, mysterious magical words
奇想天外！　さあいつまでも　神様 仏様 うさぎ様
Fantastically unexpected! Now and forever, God, Buddha, Rabbit-sama
月に祈って拝んで　義理思って　半端な気持ちを断ち切って
とりあえずいざ黙ってついてこい　フォローミー！
Pray and bow to the moon, remember your duties, cut off half-hearted feelings
For now, just follow me in silence, follow me!
あーーーーーー！
Aaaaaaaah!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい！
Lighting up your future is as easy as pie, pie, pie!
百花繚乱　大和撫子たちよ　どでかい花火を上げましょうね
A riot of flowers, O Yamato Nadeshikos, let's set off some massive fireworks
ほら踊る阿呆に見る阿呆　同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損
Look, there are dancing fools and watching fools; if you're both fools, you might as well dance
さあみんなダンス！ダンス！ダンス！　拳入って　おへそチラリ
Now everyone dance! Dance! Dance! Put some spirit into it, a peek at your belly button
靴脱いだら　そっかそっか　破れてるん
When I took off my shoes, oh I see, oh I see, they have holes in them
どったんばったんこのステージ　これが私にとっての聖地
Stomping around on this stage, this is my sacred ground
そっと！そっと！　羽ばたくんだ　聞こえるんだ　ソレ！ソレ！ソレ！ソレ！
Gently! Gently! Flapping wings, I can hear it! Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
しっ！しっ！しっ！　胸張って　みんなキラリ　つまずいても　キュンキュンくるしいの
Shih! Shih! Shih! Chest out, everyone's sparkling, even if you trip, it's a heart-throbbing pain
まとめはそれでいいのだ　マイナスも味方にしちゃうのだ
The summary is fine like that, we'll even make the negatives our allies
最高潮！愛してるんだ！　みんな大好き！　ダダダダダダッ　ブレイクダウン！
The climax! I love you! I love everyone! Da-da-da-da-da-da, Breakdown!
よーーっ、はい！
Yo---, Hai!
疾風迅雷！　どこまでも　ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
With lightning speed! To the ends of the earth, look, break through with full power
あっちもこっちもそっちも　お祭りだワッショイ　あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
大和撫子　ええなもし　不思議な言霊
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a festival, Wasshoi! A magnificent, magnificent adventure
Yamato Nadeshiko, how lovely, mysterious magical words
奇想天外！　さあいつまでも　神様 仏様 うさぎ様
Fantastically unexpected! Now and forever, God, Buddha, Rabbit-sama
月に祈って拝んで　義理思って　半端な気持ちを断ち切って
とりあえずいざ黙ってついてこい　フォローミー！
Pray and bow to the moon, remember your duties, cut off half-hearted feelings
For now, just follow me in silence, follow me!
あーーーーーー！
Aaaaaaaah!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい！
Lighting up your future is as easy as pie, pie, pie!
よっ、はい！
Yo, Hai!
満月の下で踊りましょう　サクラ舞い散る季節
Let's dance under the full moon, in the season when cherry blossoms flutter
歌いましょう　君といつかまた出会うその日まで
Let's sing, until the day we meet again with you
お日様も　お月様も　八百万も　あなた様も
The sun, the moon, all the gods, and you too
忘れないで　バイバイさようなら
Don't forget, bye-bye, goodbye
バイバーイ！
Bye-ba-i!
逃げない!!
作詞：小林愛 作曲：M87
Nigenai!!
Lyrics: Ai Kobayashi Music: M87
時間だってば 事務的にやってくる
Time, it comes around like routine work.
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow.
逃げたい じゃあどこに 逃げればいいのかな
I want to run away. Well, where should I run to?
曖昧な場所では 何も変われない
In an ambiguous place, nothing can change.
立ち向かえとか やり直せるよとか 間違った道を
'Stand up' or 'You can start over.' Down the wrong path...
何度もやり直させられる あなた一体誰ですか？
Being made to start over again and again. Who on earth are you?
論点ずれてる人達なんか押しのけて
Pushing aside people who are missing the point,
自分の道作らなくちゃ
I've got to make my own path.
失敗しないなんて 契約を人は誰とも 結んではいない
No one has signed a contract with anyone saying they won't fail.
幸せになりますとは 皆いつか大事な人と 昔約束したはずだ
Everyone must have promised someone important long ago that they'd be happy.
大人になるために 早く忘れることだけ覚え
To become adults, if we only learn to forget quickly,
無理に目を背けたら 10年後の子供を救えないよ
And force ourselves to look away, we won't be able to save children 10 years from now.
全部自分が悪いと 責める君に伝えたい
I want to tell you, who blames yourself for everything,
同じ言葉を人に 言わない君を誰も責められない
That no one can blame you for not saying the same words to others.
逃げない じゃあどこに 向かえばいいのかな
I won't run away. Well, where should I head?
辛さの根源を 見つめ直せる場所
A place where I can re-examine the source of my pain.
いきなり空を飛ぶ 方法なんて知らない
I don't know any way to suddenly fly in the sky.
悪と暇の行き来は 誰ももうしないで！
No one, go between evil and idleness anymore!
生きろとか 蘇れとか もういい もういい
'Live' or 'Be reborn,' enough, enough.
逆に逃げても いいんだよとか言う 私は一体誰ですか？
'It's okay to run away too,' who on earth am I to say that?
笑ってくれている 瞳の輝きが
The sparkle in your eyes as you laugh,
消えてないって 証明してくれた 人たちがいる
There are people who proved that it hasn't gone out.
時間だってば 事務的にやってくる
Time, it comes around like routine work.
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow.
足に訊ねる 走れるか
Asking my feet if they can run.
指に訊ねる 開けるか
Asking my fingers if they can open.
体温に訊ねる
Asking my body temperature.
血潮で導いて いけるだろうか
Can I go, guided by my lifeblood?
始まりの合図は 他の誰にも決めさせたくない
I don't want anyone else to decide the signal to start.
教科書の先の現代は 我々が作っていくから
Because we'll create the modern era beyond the textbooks.
だから逃げない 私は逃げない
So I won't run away. I won't run away.
逃げたい君を 置いてはゆかない
I won't leave you, who wants to run away.
じゃなきゃ意味ない 話したいことない
Otherwise it's meaningless. I have nothing to talk about.
顔を見なくなって 君を知ってる
I know you even after I stop seeing your face.
苦しめる渦の中
In the middle of the agonizing whirlpool,
頭脳の目広げて
Open the eyes of your brain,
別の角度で見てごらん
And look from a different angle.
そこだけ逃げないで
Don't run away from just that.
時間だってば 事務的にやってくる
Time, it comes around like routine work.
明日なんて 我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow.
とくべちゅ、して
作詞：指原莉乃 作曲：諸島健太 / 廣池博人
Tokubechu, shite
Lyrics: Rino Sashihara Music: Kenta Morishima / Hiroto Hiroike
「とくべちゅ、して？」
"Make it special?"
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough
一番　大事がいい
Being your number one is what I want
君が作るオリジナルの
The original thing that you create
特別、チューして。
Give me a special kiss.
眩しくて目が覚めて
It's so bright that I wake up
愛おしく思ってよ
Please think of me fondly
眠り姫のように
Just like Sleeping Beauty
優しく口付けて
Kiss me gently
ゴミめいたこの世界
In this world that's like trash
ピュアがかる君がいる
There you are, with your pure aura
全てに触れずに
Without touching anything
2人だけでいよう
Let's just be the two of us
私のこと独占して
Keep me all to yourself
君だけのモノになってもいい
I don't mind becoming yours alone
なんでもある日の
On a day where everything exists
「なんでもない」気付いてね
Please notice the "nothing"
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special one"
ねえもっと Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, give me more kisses, I'm already
君でいっぱいよ
filled with thoughts of you
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指ギュッて縛って
Tie our pinky fingers tight
そうよ一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want us to be together forever
とくベチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss
2人きり週末は
On weekends when it's just the two of us
奏でてよハーモニー
Play a harmony for me
流れ星見たら
If you see a shooting star
私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me
あまあまな君なのに
Even though you're so sweet
広い街吸い込まれ
Swallowed up by the wide city
戦う姿に
In your fighting figure
大きい はなまるだね
I'll give you a big gold star
好きなところ、優しいとこ。
The things I like, your kindness.
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ。
Even the things I hate, your kindness.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone
私だけ独り占め！
I'll keep you all to myself!
う～だって今までの人と
Well, because I don't want the same
同じはいらないんです
as people up until now
ねえもっと Give me more love 私のため
Hey, give me more love for my sake
生きてほしいんです
I want you to live
だからウサギと私は
That's why bunnies and I
さみしくさせないで
Don't let us get lonely
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not enough to be called restraint
苦しいのが好き
I like the painful feeling
ショートケーキイチゴみたいに
Like a strawberry on a shortcake
座ってもいい？
Can I sit there?
赤く甘いもんだもん
Because it's red and sweet
誰かにあげた大好きも
Even the "love" you gave someone else
返してもらって全部私に
Get it back and give it all to me
ちょーだい
Give it to me
もっと！
More!
君は神様が作る
You are a miracle-like person
奇跡のようなヒト
Created by God
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your sulky face and your sleeping face
守ってあげるね
I'll protect them for you
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special one"
ねえもっと Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, give me more kisses, I'm already
君でいっぱいよ
filled with thoughts of you
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指ギュッて縛って
Tie our pinky fingers tight
ねえ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, make this our first and last
とくベチュにしてね
special kiss
ミルクで乾杯～
A toast with milk!
止まらんあま～い
Unstoppably sweet
レンジでチンしてあったかい
Warm it up in the microwave
レッツゴー ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's go, Pa-pi-pu-pe-POP!
人生万歳
Long live life!
この先10年安泰
Safe for the next 10 years
盛れバズったらはんぱな～い
If it goes viral, it'll be insane!
レッツゴー ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's go, Pa-pi-pu-pe-POP!
ぴょんぴょんですびゅんびゅんです
Boing boing, zoom zoom
るんるんですぴかぴかですハッピーです
Humming, sparkling, happy!
問題ないっす半端ないっす我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, it's insane, we're discotheque bambinas
テキトーですイージーです曖昧ですずっとこうやって
Random, easy, vague, let's keep doing this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Living pop in a Pa-pi-pu-pe-Po way
毎日毎日パーティーピーポー
Every day, every day, party people
Let me yeah! だい！縦ノリ 横ノリ 悪ノリです
Let me yeah! Die! Vertical sway, horizontal sway, bad vibes!
映画のキャストみたいに ボンキュのボンな美ボディ
Like a movie cast, a curvaceous beautiful body
弾けてスマイルデライト
Bursting with smile delight
なんでスネてんの？ (うるさい！)
Why are you sulking? (Shut up!)
なんで泣いてんの？ (あっちいって！)
Why are you crying? (Go away!)
なんで？
Why?
だって
Because
女の子だもん
I'm a girl
なんで帰っちゃうの？
Why are you going home?
（触んないで！）
(Don't touch me!)
なんで怒ってんの？
Why are you angry?
あーもうわかってよ
Ah, geez, just understand
言わなくてもわかってよ
Understand without me saying it
とりあえずごめん
For now, I'm sorry
やっぱ好きー！
I love you after all!
めんどくさっ
What a pain
ぴゅんぴゅんです ぴゅんぴゅんです
I'm zoom-zooming, I'm zoom-zooming
るんるんです きゃーです
I'm humming, I'm screaming
はっぴーです
I'm happy
問題ないっす 半端ないっす
No problem, it's incredible
我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
We are discotheque Bambinas
テキトーです イージーです
I'm easy-going, it's easy
曖昧です ずっとこうやって
I'm vague, let's keep doing this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly in a PaPiPuPePo way
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po
Hi! Hi!
ぱっと咲いて shy
Blooming suddenly, shy
ピアニッシモで kiss
With a pianissimo kiss
プロいラップ yo
Pro-level rap, yo
ペプシ飲んで お〜
Drinking Pepsi, oh~
ポップに踊ろう
Let's dance poppingly
さぁ Let's
Now, let's
さぁ Let's Go!
Now, let's go!
Funny Funny time!
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
ぎゅんです 3 2 1
It's a squeeze, 3 2 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
おこです 3 2 1
I'm angry, 3 2 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
笑顔で 3 2 1
With a smile, 3 2 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe
変顔 3 2 1
Funny face, 3 2 1
なんかいい感じ
Feeling good somehow
もしもしー？
Hello?
なんか嬉しいわ
I'm happy somehow
どうしたん？
What's wrong?
なんか、なんか、やっぱ、やっぱ、女の子だもん
Somehow, somehow, after all, after all, I'm a girl
なんかハッピーです
I'm happy somehow
うん、それで？
Yeah, and then?
なんか有頂天です
I'm on cloud nine somehow
あーもう
Ah, geez
幸せです！
I'm happy!
聞いてよ！
Listen to me!
幸せです！
I'm happy!
ちょっと話してってば！
Let's talk for a bit!
さぁ聞いてー！
Now, listen!
へーそうなんだ...
Heh, is that so...
最高です 絶好です
It's the best, it's perfect
ミラクルです チョベリグです
It's a miracle, it's very good
ハイパーです
It's hyper
とんでもないっす 尋常ないっす
It's incredible, it's unusual
我々アーティスティックなバンビーナ
We are artistic Bambinas
ちょっとだけ ポンコツです
Just a little bit klutzy
太公望です ずっとこうやって
I'm a visionary, let's keep doing this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly in a PaPiPuPePo way
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po
ミルクで乾杯〜
Cheers with milk~
砂糖混ぜたらあまーい
Mixing in sugar makes it sweet
レンジでチンしてあったかーい
Pop it in the microwave to make it warm
Let's go
ぱぴぷぺぽー
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po~
人生万歳〜
Long live life~
この先10年安泰〜
The next 10 years will be safe and sound~
これでバズったら半端な〜い
It'll be insane if this goes viral~
Let's go
ぱぴぷぺぽー
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po~
ぱぴ ぱぴ ぱぴ ぱぴ ぱぴ ぱぴ
Pa-pi, pa-pi, pa-pi, pa-pi, pa-pi, pa-pi
Poppin' POP!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa pi pu pe po, pa pi pu pe po, pa pi pu pe po
愛チュセヨ Lovin' you
Please give me love, lovin' you
アモーレ アミーゴ
Amore, amigo
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa pi pu pe po, pa pi pu pe po, pa pi pu pe po
ABCDEFGHIJKLMN
A B C D E F G H I J K L M N
OPPO People People
O P P O People People
Be Poppin' Poppin' Poppin' Poppin' Poppin' Poppin'
Pop Pop Pop Pop!
最大級 最高級 最上級 ハイスペックな人生です
Maximum class, top class, superlative, it's a high-spec life
アイラブユー アイフォーユー
I love you, I for you
誰より君が一番だと思いな
Believe that you are number one above all others
ほんとはね やっぱりね
To tell the truth, after all
結局ね ずっとこうやって
In the end, let's keep doing this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly in a PaPiPuPePo way
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po
ぴゅんぴゅんです ぷにゅぷにゅです
I'm zoom-zooming, I'm squish-squishing
るんるんです きゃーです
I'm humming, I'm screaming
はっぴーです
I'm happy
問題ないっす 半端ないっす
No problem, it's incredible
我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
We are discotheque Bambinas
テキトーです イージーです
I'm easy-going, it's easy
曖昧です ずっとこうやって
I'm vague, let's keep doing this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly in a PaPiPuPePo way
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
In a PaPiPuPePo way
ポップにエンジョイ
Enjoy poppingly
あれこれどれそれ楽しいね
This and that, all of it is fun
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
In a PaPiPuPePo way
ポップにエンジョイ
Enjoy poppingly
あれこれどれそれ楽しいね
This and that, all of it is fun
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa Pi Pu Pe Po
Poppin' POP!
みんな、ゲストパートどうだった？
Everyone, how was the guest segment?
可愛かった？
Was it cute?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
ということでね、すごい続けてやってしまったんですが。
So, I ended up doing it all in one go.
まず、『サクラアプロイシュ』はAZKiとルーナちゃんと莉々華に出てもらいました。
First, for 'Sakura Apparition', I had AZKi, Luna-chan, and Ririka join me.
なんかすごい桜というか、春っぽいね、ピンクな感じのメンバーをね、呼びました。
I invited members who give off a pink, cherry blossom, or spring-like vibe.
莉々華すごい頑張ってたよなぁ。
Ririka really worked hard.
すごいね、練習中も『あぁーできない！』って言いながらね、頑張ってた莉々華。
Ririka gave it her all, even saying 'Aah, I can't do it!' during practice.
そして次、『逃げない』。
And next, 'Nigenai'.
逃げないはちょっと結構古めの曲なんですけど、まつりがすごいすごい大好きで、
'Nigenai' is a fairly old song, but I really, really love it,
一番推していた、ゆるめるモ！さんの楽曲で、あの、ここで歌えてすごく嬉しかったです。
It's a song by You'll Melt More!, my favorite group. I was so happy to sing it here.
ありがとうございますね。
Thank you so much.
そして、『特不自然』は、もう難しかった！
And 'Tokufushizen' was just so difficult!
すごい難しかったんだから。だってさ、1番と2番さ、サビの振りも違うしさ、めちゃ難しかったよ。
It was really tough. The chorus choreography is different between the first and second verses.
いや、＝LOVEさんの曲は毎回難しいけど、すごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね。
=LOVE's songs are always hard, but they're so much fun to dance to.
はい。そして、『ぱぴぷぺぽポップ』。
Yes. And 'PaPiPuPePo Pop'.
これ、あの、ずっとこうやってるから、すごい疲れて、あの、汗だくになった。
Because of the constant movement, it was exhausting and I got drenched in sweat.
もうすごかったよ。練習中の時の時も汗だくすぎて、『ちょっと待って、ちょっと疲れた』とか言ってね、
It was intense. During practice, I was so sweaty I'd say, 'Wait, I'm a bit tired,'
みんなでわちゃわちゃしながらね、練習もしましたけど。すごい楽しいでございました。
We practiced while having a lot of fun together. It was really enjoyable.
はい、そしてちょっと紹介できてなかった、こちらのステージ！
Okay, and I haven't introduced it yet, but look at this stage!
じゃーん！可愛い。
Ta-da! It's so cute.
すごい可愛くね、作っていただきました。
They made it look so adorable for me.
あ、あの、
Ah, um...
アイドルソングたちばかりなので、
Since there are mostly idol songs,
アイドルステージっていう感じにしてくださいって言って、
I asked them to make it an idol stage,
こんな感じになりましたよ。
and it turned out like this.
あの、提灯もね、あるけどさ、
Um, there are lanterns too, but
なんかすごい、あの、主張しすぎないというか良い意味でね、
they don't stand out too much, in a good way.
あの、なんかパステルなピンクとか、ま、これ色変わるんですけど、
Um, like the pastel pink, and the colors change,
すごい可愛い感じにしてくれて、
they made it really cute,
で、風船もね、これね、色変わるんですよ、実はね。
and the balloons, they actually change colors too.
なんかちょっとそこら辺も注目していただきたいなと思いますね。
I'd like you to pay attention to that too.
めっちゃ可愛いですよ。
It's so cute.
あの、後で一個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います。(笑)
Um, I think I'll take one home later. (laughs)
はい。そして、あのね、みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど、
Yes. And, um, I wonder if everyone noticed,
あのね、まつりすがね、いるわけですよ。
um, Matsurisu are here.
そう、あのね、周年、1期生の周年ライブの時にはいなかったんですよ。
Right, um, they weren't there for the anniversary live.
ね、エビフライオンがいたの、代わりに。
See, Ebi Fry Lion was there instead.
他の、さ、はあとんとかはさ、あの、ちゃんとはあとんとしていたのに、
Others, like Haaton, were there properly as Haaton,
リスナーさんの姿でいたのに、まつりだけ、まつりすがいなくて、
they were in their listener forms, but only for Matsuri,
エビフライオンだったんで、今回、あの、良かったね、これって。
it was Ebi Fry Lion, so this time it's good, right?
ということで、早速続いての曲いきましょうか。
So, let's move on to the next song right away.
続いてもアイドルソングでございますよ。
The next one is an idol song as well.
それでは聴いてください。「アイドルソング」。
Please listen to it. "IDOL SONG".
ねぇ　アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give a lot of love
この命の使い道を
I want this life's purpose
君に愛されたい
to be loved by you
IDOL SONG
作詞・作曲：大森靖子
Lyrics/Composition: Seiko Oomori
はい！一番おいしい落とし穴
Yes! The most delicious pitfall
夢中にさせちゃうぞ！
I'll make you fall for me!
埼玉県から来ました！
I'm from Saitama Prefecture!
フレッシュレモンになりたいの〜！
I want to be a fresh lemon~!
ファンの方が恋人です！
The fans are my lovers!
真面目なアイドル年中無休！
A serious idol, open all year round!
24時間ずっと笑顔でうさちゃんピース！
Always smiling 24 hours a day, bunny peace!
はい！
Yes!
あなたの心に、はーびーむ！
In your heart, Ha-Beam!
あなたのハートにアクセスします！
I'm accessing your heart!
みんなのドキドキにシュートします！
I'll shoot for everyone's heartbeats!
なんでもいいからレス下さい！
Give me any kind of response!
はげ気味のみなさん！
To all of you who are balding!
うおー！
Whoa!
よし！
Alright!
今日も可愛い！
Cute today as well!
小指！
Pinky!
ねぇ　アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
理屈はわからないけど
I don't know the logic behind it, but
幸せに満ちてるシャンプーの
I found a scent like shampoo
香りを見つけたの
that's filled with happiness
歌で人の気持ち
I want to make
明るくできるように
people feel brighter through song
きっと人生にくじけてる
Because I think there are people
人がいると思うから
who are discouraged in life
はい！好きでいよう　もっと簡単に
Yes! Let's keep loving, more simply
はい！好きでいよう　もっと叫べ　イェーイ！
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more, yeah!
はい！好きでいよう　もっと簡単に
Yes! Let's keep loving, more simply
はい！好きでいよう　もっと叫べ　イェーイ！
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more, yeah!
はい！めちゃくちゃ話すのが苦手
Yes! I'm incredibly bad at talking
可愛い自分気持ち悪い
A cute version of myself is gross
世の中のルール歌って踊って破壊する！
Singing and dancing to break the world's rules!
燃えるド根性！
Burning fighting spirit!
燃える髪の毛！
Burning hair!
見た目は純白中身は真っ黒
Pure white on the outside, pitch black on the inside
ちょっぴりおバカな小さな巨人
A slightly stupid little giant
完全勝利！
Total victory!
みるくとみゆきを混ぜるだけ
Just mix milk and Miyuki
あっという間にみるきー！
And in no time, you get Milky!
ちちんぷいぷい魔法にかかれ！
Abra-cadabra, let the magic take hold!
あ、かかっちゃった！
Oh, you fell for it!
トイレなんて行ったことないよ
I've never even been to the bathroom
ピンクのマシュマロが出ます！
Pink marshmallows come out!
3時のおやつはマカロンが良き！
Macarons are good for a 3 o'clock snack!
ふわふわガール目指し中！
Aiming to be a fluffy girl!
ねぇ　アイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun
いっぱい愛が回ってる
There's so much love going around
ステージから見る景色が
The view from the stage
ずっと宝物さ
will always be a treasure
でももし君が
But even if you
挫折したとしても
were to fail
君が救う分の幸せを
as much happiness as you save
あげられていたかな
I wonder if I was able to give it to you
はい！好きでいよう　もっと大胆に
Yes! Let's keep loving, more boldly
はい！好きでいよう　もっと叫べ　イェーイ！
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more, yeah!
はい！好きでいよう　もっと大胆に
Yes! Let's keep loving, more boldly
はい！好きでいよう　もっと叫べ　ふぅー！
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more, woo-hoo!
はい！360度どこから見ても
Yes! From any 360-degree angle
アイドル！
Idol!
出席番号ラッキーセブン！
Attendance number lucky seven!
好きになってもいいですか？
Is it okay if I fall for you?
僕の妹がこんなに可愛いわけがないと
My little sister can't be this cute
超プリプリピチピチでしょ？
Super perky and fresh, right?
こんにちはー！メリメリ！
Hello~! Mery-mery!
推せる愛せるランドセル
A lovable school bag you can support
今日も明日も明後日も
Today, tomorrow, and the day after
キラキラパワー全開！
Full sparkling power!
がんばっていったー！
Did my best-er!
みんなの目線は
Everyone's gaze is on
いただきまゆゆ！
Itadaki-Mayuyu!
泣き虫で甘えん坊な
The crybaby and pampered
みんなの妹
everyone's little sister
ねぇ　アイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun
いっぱい愛が回ってる
There's so much love going around
ステージから見る景色が
The view from the stage
ずっと...
will always...
…とどけたいおもいのさ
...of the feelings I want to deliver.
ねぇアイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you so much love.
この命の使い方を
This way of using my life...
君に愛されていたい
I want to be loved by you.
はい！好きでいよう もっと簡単に
Yes! Let's keep loving, even more simply.
はい！好きでいよう もっと叫んで
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more.
はい！好きでいよう もっと簡単に
Yes! Let's keep loving, even more simply.
はい！好きでいよう もっと叫んで
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more.
はい！好きでいよう もっと大胆に
Yes! Let's keep loving, even more boldly.
はい！好きでいよう もっと叫んで
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more.
はい！好きでいよう もっと大胆に
Yes! Let's keep loving, even more boldly.
はい！好きでいよう もっと叫んで
Yes! Let's keep loving, shout it out more.
行け 優しさ 絆 キラキラ輝け 頑張っていきまーしょい！
Go! Kindness, bonds, sparkle and shine. Let's do our best!
わん！びっくりしたでしょ？
Woof! You were surprised, weren't you?
今日の私が昨日より可愛いなんて！
That the me today is even cuter than yesterday!
ちゅーぎゅ♡ 作詞・作曲：大森靖子
Chu-gyu♡ Lyrics/Composition: Seiko Omori
ぎゅっちゅぎゅっちゅぎゅして
Hug, hug, hug me.
次の流行りは次の地雷 踏まないように知っとかなくちゃ
The next trend is the next landmine, I gotta know so I don't step on it.
でもぎゅっとしたら大爆発
But if we hug, there's a big explosion.
ばっちり第一に大事に抱きたくない 知りたくない ずっと閉じたらスピン
Perfectly, first and foremost, I don't want to hold it dear, I don't want to know. If I close it forever, it spins.
なぜなぜわからないだらけのワンダーランド
Why, oh why, is it a wonderland full of unknowns?
私 ちゅちゅちゅ ちゅぎゅ
I'm chu-chu-chu Chu-gyu.
ぎゅ！
Hug!
絶好最高潮
At the absolute peak.
未来絶好調
Future is in top form.
絶好最大等
Absolute maximum and such.
未来肯定だ
Future is an affirmation.
未来ちらちら 福袋みたい
Future flickering like a lucky bag.
綺麗な色が見えたから
Because I saw beautiful colors...
これにしよう
...let's go with this.
さあ待ってな Yeah!
Now wait for it, Yeah!
ちゅぎゅ！
Chu-gyu!
ちゅぎゅ！ ちゅぎゅ！
Chu-gyu! Chu-gyu!
妥協はしないわ しちゃう中二病
I won't compromise, even with my Chuunibyou.
間違っても可愛いとなれるうちに
While I can still be cute even if I'm wrong.
一番可愛いとき君といたいなら 全然心配しないで
If you want to be with me when I'm cutest, don't worry at all.
私 ちゅちゅちゅ ちゅぎゅ
I'm chu-chu-chu Chu-gyu.
私 ちゅちゅちゅ 死んでる暇ない可愛いと言いたい
I'm chu-chu-chu, I have no time to die, I want to say I'm cute.
絶好最高潮
At the absolute peak.
未来絶好調
Future is in top form.
今は絶好調
Right now is in top form.
未来全部入り
Future included in full.
素敵な夢が
A wonderful dream...
好きな私で
...with the me I like.
ひとつすごく素敵な
A single, very wonderful...
女の子でいよう
...girl I'll be.
何歳になっても可愛いね、じゃないの！
It's not 'you're cute no matter how old you get'!
こっちは努力して可愛いやってんの！
I'm putting in the effort to be cute!
何十何歳だったら可愛いの？ 本当はそんなの当たり前だもん。
At what age is it cute? Actually, that's obvious.
言わせないでよ。
Don't make me say it.
そっちから言って。 今日も可愛いね、でしょ？
You say it first. 'You're cute today too,' right?
今日も可愛いね。
You're cute today too.
可愛いね。
You're cute.
可愛い！
So cute!
今日も可愛い！
You're cute today too!
私、今日も可愛いね！
Me, I'm cute today too!
よし、今日も可愛いぞ！
Alright, I'm cute today too!
未来ちらちら
Future flickering.
お料理お祝い
Cooking and celebrating.
私見せては元に戻して
Show me, then put it back.
未来ちらちら 怖いからこそ
Future flickering, because it's scary...
今想うと急に生きたい
...thinking about it now, I suddenly want to live.
絶好最高潮
At the absolute peak.
未来絶好調
Future is in top form.
絶好最大等
Absolute maximum and such.
未来肯定だ
Future is an affirmation.
未来ちらちら 福袋みたい
Future flickering like a lucky bag.
綺麗な色が見えたから
Because I saw beautiful colors...
これにしよう
...let's go with this.
さあ待ってな Yeah!
Now wait for it, Yeah!
ちゅぎゅ！
Chu-gyu!
ちゅぎゅ！ ちゅぎゅ！
Chu-gyu! Chu-gyu!
さあ出ろ！
Let's go!
君に乞うな 恋のSOS
I beg you, SOS of love.
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My heart has been aching all this time.
早くレスキュー好きのテレパシーに
Rescue me quickly, with the telepathy of love...
早く気づいて
...please notice it soon.
SOS 作詞：下地悠 作曲：睦月周平
SOS Lyrics: Yu Shimoji Composition: Shuhei Mutsuki
初めて出会ったときから
From the time we first met...
ハートが震えてたんだよ
...my heart has been trembling.
無意識に意識しちゃう
I end up conscious of it unconsciously.
この感じはきっと重症ね
This feeling is surely a serious case.
求め合うだけで顔が熱いの
Just wanting each other makes my face hot.
話しかけられて頭パニック
Being talked to makes my head panic.
一、十、百、千、万
One, ten, hundred, thousand, ten thousand
恋はずっと止まらない
This love just won't stop
どうすればいいの？
What should I do?
素直な気持ちは
These honest feelings
君との相性は
Our compatibility
星占いなら最高
Is the best according to the horoscope
友達なんかじゃないよ
We're not just friends
ときめいてる
My heart is fluttering
君に Fall in Love
I'm falling in love with you
不意の SOS
A sudden SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been aching this whole time
早くレスキュー
Rescue me quickly
好きのテレパシーに
Please notice my telepathy
早く気づいて
Of love soon
これは Fall in Love
This is falling in love
不意の SOS
A sudden SOS
もっと君に近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて片想い
End this unrequited love
My heart
全部抱きしめて
Hug my whole heart
君が好きな音楽や
The music you like and
映画のことリサーチして
Researching about movies
SNS見るたびに
Every time I check social media
いいね押すの　アピールだよ
Pressing "Like" is my way of showing it
四六時中　君のこと考えて
Thinking about you 24/7
悶絶しながら　枕投げした
Threw my pillow while writhing in agony
明日はどんな服着ていこうかな
I wonder what clothes I should wear tomorrow
君想うだけで　なんか照れる
Just thinking about you makes me blush
君の名前を呼べば
If I call out your name
ただそれだけでも Dreaming Dreaming
Even just that makes me start dreaming
溺れそうだよ私は
I'm about to drown
助け出して
Come and save me
君に Fall in Love
I'm falling in love with you
不意の SOS
A sudden SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been aching this whole time
早くレスキュー
Rescue me quickly
好きのテレパシーに
Please notice my telepathy
早く気づいて
Of love soon
これは Fall in Love
This is falling in love
不意の SOS
A sudden SOS
もっと君に近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて片想い
End this unrequited love
My heart
全部抱きしめて
Hug my whole heart
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make this fresh excitement resonate
最高の時間　最高の仲間と
In this best of times, with the best of friends
キラメキ放て
Release the radiance
Yeah!
覚えてるかな　最初の歌
Do you remember our first song?
私　声が震えていた
My voice was trembling
あの日から続く未来は
The future that follows from that day
みんなと掴んだようだよ
It feels like we've grasped it together
もっともっともっと　加速するハート
More, more, more, this heart is accelerating
いくよどこまでも
I'll go anywhere
準備は OK?
Are you ready?
開け夢の扉を
Open the door to dreams
Shiny Festa! キラメキライダー!
Shiny Festa! Kirameki Rider!
かざされた手はギュッと離さずに
Without letting go of our raised hands
光　誓う　描き出すときめき
Swearing by the light, the excitement we portray
振り向くことなく真っ直ぐに
Going straight ahead without looking back
いくよ　夢見る空へ
Here I go, towards the dreaming sky
笑いあったことや
The times we laughed together
尽きそうにない課題
And the endless challenges
思い出いっぱいなのに
Even though we have so many memories
あどけない日々
Those innocent days
上書きじゃなくて
Instead of overwriting them...
なまえつけてハート
Give it a name, Heart
どれもぜんぶだいじにして
Cherish them all
いればうれしい
I'll be happy if they're there
みんなのためたちからになる
I'll be the strength for everyone
今日もにぎやかすぎるくらい
Today is almost too lively again
笑顔がもう止まらない
My smile just won't stop
想いはふくらんでいく
My feelings are growing
背伸びしては手を伸ばす
Standing on tiptoe and reaching out
憧れの...
To the one I admire...
行き先示す星になろう
I'll become a star that shows the way
つなぐその旅に 手を差し伸べあえたら
If we could reach out to each other on that connected journey
すぐに届くはずさ
I'm sure we'll reach it soon
そっと踏み出した 小さな勇気が
The small amount of courage I quietly stepped out with
もう消えないように 繋げよう
Let's connect it so it never fades away
不安も愛しさも 大切に抱きしめて
I'll cherish both my anxiety and my affection
共に行こう 目を合わせて 3-2-1!
Let's go together, eye to eye, 3-2-1!
晴れ渡る空へ
To the clear sky
飛び出せるよ 突き抜けていく
I can take off and break through
僕たちの透き通る決意今
Our transparent determination right now
まだまだ止められないよ
I can't stop just yet
ありきたりな日常を ときめきに変えてもっと
Changing ordinary days into excitement even more
僕たちがいつでも 背中を押すから
Because we'll always be there to push you forward
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage I admire
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時に涙して
Sometimes crying
また笑いあいたい
I want to laugh together again
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous first step
息切らして夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams until I'm out of breath
ワクワク止まらない
My excitement won't stop
ゾクゾク燃えていく 世界に見せてあげる
A thrill is burning up, I'll show it to the world
アクセスしてみない？
Why not try to access it?
後悔なんてここにない
There's no regret here
それぞれ違った 心で素晴らしい
Each of us is wonderful with our different hearts
はい、ということで
Yes, and with that...
ホロライブ、えにこ... ホロライブメンバー...
hololive, enico... hololive members...
自分の事務所なのに噛みました
I stumbled even though it's my own agency
いや、どうだった？ なんか激エモだったんじゃないですか？
Well, how was it? Wasn't it super emotional?
そしてね、この衣装は初めてもらったアイドル衣装なんですよ
And you know, this outfit is the first idol costume I ever received
なんか、あの時を思い出して、なんかすごいジーンときてしまいますわね
Thinking back to those days makes me feel really touched
そう、まつりはね、元々その、アイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよ、ホロライブって
That's right, for Matsuri, hololive wasn't originally an idol debut
で、この衣装をもらって、よし、アイドルとして頑張るぞというね
But after getting this costume, I remember feeling...
気持ちを改めて思い出し、頑張っていこうかなという気持ちでございます
...like 'Alright, I'm going to work hard as an idol!'
はい、そしてそして
Yes! And also...
今回も誕生日記念グッズでございまーす！ やったー！
...here are the birthday memorial goods! Yay!
嬉しい！ ということで、一つずつ紹介していきます
I'm so happy! So, I'll introduce them one by one
誕生日記念2025
Birthday Memorial 2025
まずは、こちら。 ドドーン！
First, here it is. Ta-da!
『薄すぎ！ おっぱいマウスパッド』
'Too thin! Boob mouse pad'
「薄すぎ！」おっぱいマウスパッド
"Too Thin!" Boob Mouse Pad
あ、『おっぱいマウスパッド』！ やったー！
Ah, 'Boob mouse pad'! Yay!
イラストはえく先生！ まつり待望のね、マウスパッドでございますよ
The illustration is by Eku-sensei! It's the mouse pad Matsuri has been waiting for
もう、あの、ちなみに言うと、膨らみはないです
By the way, there's no bulge
普通のマウスパッドとなっております
It's a regular mouse pad
まあ皆さんね、手首...
Well, everyone, your wrists...
ね、こうやってあの癒やすことはね、ちょっと難しいんですが、
Right, it's a bit difficult to heal you like this, but...
もうちょっとガチ照れな...
...it's like a really embarrassed...
ぎゅーみたいな感じなのでね、
...'hug' kind of feeling, so...
あのー心から癒されていくという感じで。
...it's like being healed from the heart.
はい。どうですか？素晴らしいことでございましょう。
Yes. How is it? It's wonderful, isn't it?
そして続いてこちらー！
And next is this!
じゃーん！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Ta-da! Random Acrylic Keyholders!
なんと、夏色まつり先生のね、描き下ろしでございますよ！
Unbelievably, they are newly drawn by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei herself!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー。
Random Acrylic Keyholders.
もうまつりがグッズのイラスト描くってなかなか無い代物でございますから、
It's quite rare for Matsuri to draw illustrations for her own merch,
すごい愛情込めて描きました。もう、ちゅっちゅっちゅってしながら描いたので、
so I drew them with lots of love. I drew them while going "mwah mwah mwah",
ぜひね、全種類コンプリートしてみてください！
so please try to complete the whole set!
そして続いてこちら！
And next is this!
まつりちゃんのぬいぐるみ、サブカルジャージ衣装Ver.でございます！
Matsuri-chan's plushie, Subculture Jersey Outfit Ver.!
えー、キービジュのイラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装の、なんとぬいが登場しちゃいますよー！
A plushie in the same subculture jersey outfit as the key visual is appearing!
キービジュのように押し倒すことはちょっと現実だと叶わないけど、ぬいなら、
While pushing someone down like in the key visual isn't possible in reality, with a plushie...
ぬいならできちゃう！ということで、ぜひね、たくさん可愛がって色んなところに連れて行ってあげてください。
...with a plushie you can! So please shower it with love and take it to various places.
さらにーこちら！
Furthermore, this!
まつりすマグカップ！みんなにはマグカップになってもらいました。
Matsurisu Mug! I had you all turn into mugs.
どんな罪を犯してこんな姿になっちまったんだって感じでございますが、あー、
It's like, "What sin did I commit to end up in this form?" but...
ま、自分なのでね、あのーこれが俺の姿かーって思いながら使っていただけたらなと思います。まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます。
...well, it's yourself, so I hope you use it while thinking "So this is my form". Matsuri-chan will use it too.
最後に、ボイス！じゃじゃーん！
Lastly, the Voice Pack! Ta-da!
シチュエーションボイス『逆襲のまつりす』。なんだ『逆襲のまつりす』ってなんだー？
Situation Voice: "Matsurisu's Counterattack". What? What is "Matsurisu's Counterattack"?
はい、今回ね、キービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーがここに詰まっちゃってますので、
Yes, the story leading up to the situation in the key visual is packed into this,
どんなシチュエーションなのかちょっと気になる方は、ぜひゲットしてみてください！
so if you're curious about the situation, please get it!
そして、フルセットを購入いただいた方全員に、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードが付いてきちゃいます！
And everyone who purchases the full set will get a postcard with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped duplicate message!
えーちょっとね、来年は直筆やるかちょっとまだ未定でございますので、ぜひね、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ全員に書かせていただきますので、
Um, it's still undecided if I'll do handwritten ones next year, so please, I'll be writing them for everyone,
初めてなんです、それも。全員にサイン書くの初めてだから、ぜひ手に入れてください。
it's the first time for that too. It's the first time I'm writing signatures for everyone, so please get it.
来年やるか分かんないからね。
I don't know if I'll do it next year.
さらにですね、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
Furthermore, as a full set bonus for the Talent Premium Goods,
2024年9月から発売された hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚付いてきちゃいますよー！
one card that can be used in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME, which went on sale in September 2024, is included!
まつりはね、前回のグッズでちょっと特典に付いてなかったので、今回付いてくるよーって感じになっております。
Matsuri didn't have it as a bonus with the previous merch, so it's included this time.
えー、同封する、同封であってる？日本語。はい。
Um, enclosed... is "enclosed" the right Japanese? Yes.
ホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで購入されたお客様にゃにゃにゃ…あ、お客様のみの対象となっておりますので、よろしくお願いします。
This applies only to customers... nya nya nya... ah, only to customers who purchased from the Hololive Production Official Shop, so thank you.
特典に付くのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードでございます！
The bonus is a "Oshi Holomen Card", a key card where you can use only one in the game and show off your "oshi"!
そしてそしてそして！さらにでございますよ！まだある！
And, and, and! There's even more! There's still more!
アルバム！ででででででん！なんとまつりちゃん、ファーストアルバム『Chasing the Dream』
An Album! Da-da-da-da-da! Believe it or not, Matsuri-chan's first album, "Chasing the Dream"...
『スポットライトは放課後に』が、なんと本日11月1日受注開始でございますー！ぱんぱかぱーん！
..."Spotlight wa Houkago ni", is open for orders today, November 1st! Pam-paka-pam!
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲『君と眺める夏の花』を始め、これまでに配信リリースしてきた作品のほか、
Starting with Matsuri-chan's first original song "Kimi to Nagameru Natsu no Hana", as well as works released digitally so far,
じんさん始め豪華作曲陣が書き下ろしてくださった新規楽曲も収録しちゃってますよー！
it also includes new songs written by a luxurious team of composers including Jin-san!
計14曲の超ボリューミーなアルバムになっているので、ぜひ手に入れちゃってください！
It's a very voluminous album with a total of 14 songs, so please get your hands on it!
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと、普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんのこう両面みたいな、両方が楽しめるようなアルバムになってます。
The concept is like both sides of Matsuri-chan—the idol and the everyday high school girl—so you can enjoy both.
えー形態は2つありまして、完全生産限定盤と通常盤をご用意してあります。
There are two versions: the Limited Edition and the Regular Edition.
完全生産限定盤はですね、セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーが付いてきちゃいますよー！
The Limited Edition comes with a separate-type original calendar!
そして両形態に封入特典として、まつりちゃんからの複製お手紙が入っています。
And as an enclosed bonus for both versions, there's a duplicate letter from Matsuri-chan.
ただし、数量限定のランダムでですね、複製お手紙の代わりに直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が封入されていますので、ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください！
However, in a limited random selection, notice that you can get a handwritten letter instead of a duplicate one will be enclosed, so please get it!
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album information!
そしてなんと、アルバムに収録する新曲のうち一曲をですね、
And what's more, for one of the new songs included in my album,
本日この後披露しちゃいまーす！
I'll be performing it right here today!
タイトルは、
The title is...
「ウーニャカ」！
"U-nyaka"!
作曲はですね、かめりあさんに作曲いただきました。
It was composed by Camellia.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It's so incredibly cute!
MVもですね、この後プレミア公開ありますので、
The MV will also have a premiere after this,
0時から、あの、楽曲リリースもありますので、
and since the song will be released at midnight,
あの、是非よろしくお願いしますね。
so please be sure to check it out.
プレミア公開、プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね。はい。
Let's watch the premiere, let's watch the premiere together. Okay.
じゃあ、ちょっと着替えてきますので、
Well then, I'm going to go change,
ちょっとここで待ってて、
so please wait here for a bit,
「ワクワク」って言いながら、あの、ゲストパートと同じように
and while saying "Waku-waku," just like in the guest part,
「ワクワク」って言いながら待っててください。
please wait while saying "Waku-waku."
じゃ、行ってきまーす！
Okay, I'm off!
ワクワク、ワクワク。
Waku-waku, waku-waku.
ウーニャカ
作詞・作曲：かめりあ
編曲：UtopiaLyric
U-nyaka
Lyrics/Composition: Camellia
Arrangement: UtopiaLyric
真夜中にトゲタ感情は爪立てて
Midnight, thorny emotions sharpen their claws
檻から見慣れた世界は牙向いて
The familiar world from within the cage shows its fangs
真夜中見かねた感情は飢えた目で
Midnight, unbearable emotions with starving eyes
軽やかに逃げた優しさ求めて
Lightly fled, searching for kindness
「愛されたい」の想い 愛されないの Give me
"I want to be loved," that feeling. I'm not loved, give me
「愛してる」も重い？ 愛さないの？もういい？
Is "I love you" too heavy? You won't love me? Is that enough?
愛情結晶頂戴 あなたを見てるのじゃ
Give me the crystal of affection, for I am watching you
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, begging
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めいっぱい
Come on, tame me, more, with all you've got
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おでかけ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, going out?
しがみついて 何処も行かせない！
Clinging to you, I won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me a sweet candy
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
叱らないで頂戴な
Please don't scold me
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true "love"
縄張り土足で感情目丸くして
Trampling on my territory, emotions wide-eyed
幸せになれた未来が牙向いて
The future where I could have been happy shows its fangs
突き放さないでいて 切り捨てず傍で
Don't push me away, don't discard me, stay by my side
お傍で お傍で お傍で見ているのじゃ
By my side, by my side, I'm watching you from by your side
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねがい
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, please
さあ頭撫でて もっと ぜーいっぱい
Come on, stroke my head, more, with everything
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おあずけ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, on hold?
甘えて泣いて 此処に居させて！
Acting spoiled, crying, let me stay here!
ニャンニャカ 言ったって 伝わんない？
Even if I say "Nyan-nyaka," it doesn't get through?
どーしたって こーしたって 寂しいの
No matter what I do, I'm lonely
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おもいっきり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, with all my heart
あざとい声 わざと聞かせる
Letting you hear my manipulative voice on purpose
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, begging
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めいっぱい
Come on, tame me, more, with all you've got
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おやすみ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, goodnight?
しがみついて 今夜寝かせない！
Clinging to you, I won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me a sweet candy
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
抱きしめて頂戴な
Please hold me tight
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nyan u-nyan-nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true "love"